const AphistoryPrintingQuestions = [
	{
		questionText: 'Satya Duta',
		ans: ['Ballari Christain Missionary'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'First Telugu paper',
		ans: ['Satya Duta'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'HitaVaadi',
		ans: ['Admand shakki'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'First Telugu paper which printed in AP',
		ans: ['HitaVaadi'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Varthamaan Tarangini',
		ans: ['Rayyath Rahamatulla'],
	},
	{
		questionText: '1st Muslim telugu Paper',
		ans: ['Varthamaan Tarangini by Rayyath Rahamatulla'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'The Crisent',
		ans: ['Gajula Laxmi Narasamma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Tatawa Bhaodini',
		ans: ['Madras Vedh samaj', 'To spread Hindusim'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Viveka Vardhini',
		ans: ['Kandukur veresa Lingam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Hasya Sanjeevani',
		ans: ['Kandukur veresa Lingam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Kandukur veresa Lingam\'s',
		ans: ['Viveka Vardhini', 'Viveka Vardhini', ''],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Andhra Prakasika',
		ans: ['A.P Pardha saradhi Nayaudu'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Krishna Patrika',
		ans: ['Dasu Narayana', 'Mutturi Krishna rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Andhra Bharati',
		ans: ['Mutturi Krishna rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Andhra Pratrika',
		ans: [
			'Kasi Nageswar Rao',
			'1st used to be weekly magzine, later changed to daily',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Bharati Patrika',
		ans: ['Kasi Nageswar Rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Sujana Prayodhini',
		ans: ['Amchata Sankyayaana Sharma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Kalpa Latha',
		ans: ['Amchata Sankyayaana Sharma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Vazra Yuddam',
		ans: ['Sri Pada Krishna Murttty'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Vidvan Manoharari',
		ans: ['Sujayat Ali Khan'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Sahi Reakha',
		ans: ['Gattu Palli Shesha Chari'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Soundara Valli',
		ans: ['Rambayi', 'Wife of Gadi Charla Sarvothama Rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Savitri',
		ans: ['Pula Gutti Laxmi Narasamba'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Anasuya',
		ans: ['Vinja Mutry Venkata Rantamma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Hindu sundarai',
		ans: ['Musali Kanti RamaBayamma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Abala Sath Charitra',
		ans: ['Accha Mamba'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Suvarna Reka',
		ans: ['Panugantala Laxmi Narashimha Rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Sri Venka Vara Patrika',
		ans: [
			'Srinivasulu Rao',
			'later named to SWARAJYA',
			'Later taken over by GadiCharla Hari Srvaothama ',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Telugu Janana',
		ans: ['Malladi venkarta Ratam', 'co- Tanguturi Veresa Lingam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Purushardha Pradaniya',
		ans: [
			'Uma Rangnayakulu from Machilipatam',
			'K.V. Lingam used to publish in this',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Andhra Basha Sanjivani',
		ans: ['Kokanda Venkata Ratnam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Amudrita Granda Chitamani',
		ans: ['Pundla Ramakrishnaya', 'Harish ChandraPakyanama, Chitramghada'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Chintamani',
		ans: ['Nya Pati Subbha Roa', 'Cilaka Murthy Laxmi narashimha'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Andhra Sahitya Parishat',
		ans: ['Jayanti Ramayya '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Jayanti Patrika',
		ans: ['Vishwa Nath Narayan'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Udayaini',
		ans: ['Konpala Janarthan Roa'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Vina',
		ans: ['PatiBandla Madhav Sharma'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Jwala',
		ans: ['Muddu Krishna'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Swaraj',
		ans: ['Tangutoru Prakasam Pantulu', 'English'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Madras Native Assosiation',
		ans: [
			'Founder: Gajula Laximi NarsaSetty',
			'Director: Soma sundaram Setty',
			'1st Social Reform Assosiation',
			'Worked on soving problems of people',
			'Opposed Christian Missionaries',
			'Opposed Child Marriage, Encouraged Widow Remarriage',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Madras Maha sabha',
		ans: [
			'Founder: G subbha rao',
			'Chairman: Ranga Nayudu',
			'Director: Ananda charyulu',
			'fought for Eward Bill',
			'Age , (india, England center ) civil Services',
			'Opoosed Caste System',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Kaiknada Sahiti Sabha is a Part of?',
		ans: ['Madras Maha sabha'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Kakinada Sahiti Sabha',
		ans: ['Kasi batla Bhrammayya Satri'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who is 1st person to become part of Bharmma Samaj',
		ans: ['Mannava Bucchaya Pantulu'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'where did Parthana Samaj 1st started in A.P',
		ans: ['Rajamundry'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Prominent Leaders in Bhramma samaj from A.p',
		ans: [
			'Atmuru Laxmi Narashimham',
			'K.V Lingam',
			'Raghupati Venkata Ratanam',
			'Desi Raju',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText:
      'Who got the tile \'బ్రహ్మర్షి\' for his contribution in Bhramma samaj ',
		ans: ['Raghupati Venkata Ratnam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Bhramma Samaja Trayam',
		ans: ['Raghupati Venkata Ratnam', 'Desi Raju', 'K.V Lingam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'దివ్య జ్ఞాన సమాజం',
		ans: ['Tusky, Alkart', 'Main Theme: మానవుని సేవ', 'HQ: Madras Adiyar'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who invited kurnal Alcart to AP ',
		ans: ['Pragada Subbha Rao'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who 1st transulated Gita to English',
		ans: ['Charles Wilkins'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'B.T college',
		ans: [
			'Anne Besant in Madanapalli',
			'Anne besant Papers: New India,\'Common Wheel\' ',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: '1st Principal of B.T college',
		ans: ['J H cousin', 'Margarete Cousin-Janagana Mana '],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Anne Beasant Adopted son?',
		ans: ['Jiddu Krishna Murthi'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'At The Feet Of The Master book?',
		ans: ['Jiddu Krishna Murthy'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Jiddu Krishna Murty philosophy',
		ans: ['Endeavour alone in search of truth'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Jiddu Krishna Murthy\'s school?',
		ans: ['Rishi Valley School of MadanaPalli'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Godavari Dam',
		ans: ['1847-52'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Krishna Dam',
		ans: ['1850-55'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who was 1st to introduce Social issues through Drams',
		ans: [
			'Dharmavaram Ramakrishnamacharyulu',
			'ఆంధ్ర నాటక పితామహుడు',
			'Nasar a famous \'Burra katha dramatist\'',
		],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Who was known as \'Hari katha Pitamaha\'',
		ans: ['Adi batla Narayana'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Sathi Hitabhodini',
		ans: ['KVL'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Satya samvardhini',
		ans: ['KVL'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Satya Vadhini',
		ans: ['KVL'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Hasya Vardhini',
		ans: ['Kokonda Venkata Ratnam'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'బ్రహ్మ ప్రకాశిక',
		ans: ['రఘుపతి వెంకటరత్నం నాయుడు in English'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Fellow worker',
		ans: ['రఘుపతి వెంకటరత్నం నాయుడు'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Peoples Friend',
		ans: ['రఘుపతి వెంకటరత్నం నాయుడు'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'Voice of truth',
		ans: ['దేశిరాజు పెద్దబాపయ్య'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'ఆంధ్ర సాహిత్య పరిషత్ paper & Assoiation',
		ans: ['జయంతి రామయ్య'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'దేశమాత',
		ans: ['చిలకమర్తి లక్ష్మీనరసింహ'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'మనోహర్',
		ans: ['చిలకమర్తి లక్ష్మీనరసింహ'],
	},
	{
		questionText: 'కృష్ణా పత్రిక',
		ans: ['కొండా వెంకటప్పయ్య'],
	},

];

export default AphistoryPrintingQuestions;
